https://western.edu/privacy-policy/

Skip to Main Content
UNIVERSITY UPDATES
|
Western Resources and Updates Related to COVID-19. Learn More
×
Home / Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Commitment to Individual Privacy
Western Colorado University is committed to protecting the privacy and accuracy of confidential information submitted by employees, students, and visitors to our website. We do not actively share personal information gathered. However, because Western Colorado University is a public institution, some information collected from the Western Colorado University website may be subject to the Colorado Public (Open) Records Act. Thus, in some cases we may be compelled by law to release information gathered from our Web servers. This may include server log information, email messages sent to an individual identified on the website, and information collected from Web-based forms.
Colorado Public (Open) Records Act (C.R.S. 24-72 201 et seq.)
It is the declared public policy of the State of Colorado that all public records shall be open for inspection by any person at reasonable times, except as otherwise provided by law. Public Records are defined by this law as all writings made or maintained by a state institution, such as Western Colorado University, regardless of the format or medium of the records.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. §1232g)
Western Colorado University also complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which generally prohibits the release of students’ education records without consent. FERPA only applies to currently enrolled students. A brief outline of this policy is printed annually in the Student Handbook or the entire FERPA Act may be found online at http://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/reg/ferpa/index.html
Information Collection
It is Western Colorado University’s policy to collect the least amount of personally identifiable information required to fulfill its required duties and responsibilities, to complete a particular transaction or as required by law. This policy applies to the collection of all personally identifiable information, regardless of the source or medium. For site administration functions, information, other than personal information linked to a particular individual, is collected for analysis and statistical purposes of website navigation. This information is used to help diagnose problems, assess what information is of most interest, determine technical design specifications, identify system performance and/or problem areas, and other administration functions. You may choose whether or not to provide personal information to Western Colorado University via the Internet. If you choose not to provide the personal information we request, you can still visit most of Western Colorado University’s websites, but you may be unable to access certain options, offers, and services that involve our interaction with you.
Security
Wherever your personal information may be held within Western Colorado University or on its behalf, we intend to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the information that you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure.
Browser Cookies
Some of our Web pages utilize “cookies.” A “cookie” is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect information about website activity. Some cookies may serve to recall personal information previously indicated by a Web user. Cookies created by Western Colorado University Web pages cannot be read by a third party. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser.
Tracking Technologies
Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clock stream patterns; and dates and times that our site is accessed. Our use of tracking technologies allows us to analyze trends and statistics to improve our website and your Web experience. Data used from tracking technologies is not linked to Web users’ personal information.
Third Party Services
On Western Colorado University’s behalf, third parties may provide certain services available on Western Colorado University websites. Western Colorado University may provide information, including personal information, collected on the Web to third-party service providers to help us deliver programs, products, information and services. Service providers are also an important means by which Western Colorado University maintains its website and mailing lists. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third-party service providers are obligated to protect personal information on our behalf.
Disclaimer
The information provided in this privacy statement should NOT be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or as warranting the security of information provided through this website.
Take the Next Step
Apply to Western
We understand that applying to a university can be daunting, which is why we make our admission process as simple and straightforward as possible. Learn more about applying to your program of choice at Western.
Visit Western
The best way to find out what makes Western such a special place is to experience it for yourself. Our
student-led tours give you an insider’s perspective on everything from academics to student life.
Alumni Community
We keep the Mountaineer spirit going strong within our alumni community. Whether getting together with friends at an annual event, making a donation or mentoring a student, graduates continue to play an important role in the Western community.
Select your Undergraduate Student Type
×
First-Time Freshman:
I have never attended college and am interested in earning a bachelor’s degree at Western.
Transfer: I have taken classes at another institution after earning a HS diploma and am interested in finishing a bachelor’s degree at Western.
Additional Bachelors Degree:
I have earned one bachelor’s degree and am interested in earning another at Western.
Non-Degree-Seeking:
I am interested in taking classes, but not earning a degree at Western.
